TRENT RIEK

Unreal Developer & Game Programmer

trentriek97@gmail.com · 512-964-7821 https://www.linkedin.com/in/trent-riek · https://trentriek.github.io

SUMMARY

Howdy! My name is Trent and I am an Unreal Engine Developer. I have a background in Visualization from Texas A&M with minors in Computer Science and Game Design. I enjoy coding in unreal as well as real time animation in game engines. I am excited to work with you and build amazing experiences!

WORK EXPERIENCE

JUNIOR UNREAL DEVELOPER (freelance)

REAL WORLD ONE - Freiburg, Germany - Summer 2022 - Present

- Developed VR applications for the Oculus in Unreal for pharmaceutical training.
- Implemented replicated components in Blueprints.

IMMERSIVE DESIGN INTERN

RAYTHEON INTELLIGENCE & SPACE - McKinney, TX - Summer 2021

- Developed a Obj to USDZ format converter for use with AR on mobile devices.
- Utilized FARO Laser Scanning Software to scan multiple buildings. Registered and converted scans to point clouds/meshes.

STUDENT POSITIONS

TEXAS A&M UNIVERSITY - College Station, TX - 2020-2022

- GAR (GRADUATE ASSISTANT RESEARCH) Developing an Oculus VR training program to prep nurses for Forensic Nursing.
- GAT (GRADUATE ASSISTANT TEACHER) taught basics and wrote lessons for Houdini,
 Maya & Unreal to participating TAMU students for use in research project.
- TA (TEACHING ASSISTANT) Led labs teaching Students the basics of scripting in Python within Maya software.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

SPECTRUM – Greenwood, CO – Summer 2020 (REMOTE)

- Learned the principles of containerization, practiced building containers and clusters.
- Exposure to Docker, Golang, Kubernetes, and Cluster tools (Kops, Helm, etc).

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT CO-OP

ANSYS - Austin, TX - Spring/Summer 2019

- Worked on the ACT API development team for the ANSYS Mechanical Workbench product. Fixed defects with API methods and object calls. Created documentation for workspace setup and debugging.
- Started work on implementing new recording feature within the API. Feature both recorded UI calls as API commands for user as well as replaced Jscript code.
- Ran regression tests on both Windows and Linux.

SKILLS

- Unreal
- C++, Python, C#
- Maya
- MotionBuilder
- Git & Perforce
- OpenGL

EDUCATION

MS VISUALIZATION
TEXAS A&M UNIVERSITY
2020-2022
BS VISUALIZATION
TEXAS A&M UNIVERSITY
2016-2020
MINORS
COMPUTER SCIENCE
GAME DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT

VOLUNTEER WORK

Texas A&M Habitat for Humanity, 2018 – 2022

450+ hours volunteering for the Williamson and Brazos county Affiliates

LEADERSHIP POSITIONS:

- Co-President
- Director of Fundraising
- Volunteer Coordinator
- Director of Advocacy